Giovanni Pasini

Denver, CO • gpasini93@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/giovanni-pasini

Front-end Developer | IT Consultant

IT Developer with over a decade of experience in the tech industry. I have held roles such as IT Manager, where I was responsible for overseeing networks and IT systems, and I am currently working as an IT Consultant, resolving technical issues and providing user support.

In 2022, I pursued my passion for programming by enrolling in a retraining program that took me to Taiwan for a Web Development Internship.

This experience allowed me to gain hands-on skills with modern technologies and strengthen my problem-solving abilities in an international environment.

To this day, I continue to study to improve my programming skills. I'm currently taking a course to learn TypeScript and Angular.

I am a motivated and adaptable individual, always looking for new challenges to grow professionally. I'm confident that my skills, combined with my determination, can bring value to any team I join.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Catholic University of the Sacred Heart IT Consultant

01/2024 - Present Brescia

- Managed and maintained the university's internal IT network.
- Provided technical support to faculty and staff for hardware and software issues.
- Monitored and resolved system malfunctions.
- Ensured IT security and protected sensitive data.
- Implemented new technologies to optimize operational efficiency.

Freelance Web Developer

01/2022 - Present

- Creation of websites through the Wordpress platform, also using knowledge of HTML and CSS.
- Research and use of various plugins for website development, according to customer requirements.

Rj45 01/2024 - 12/2024 Help Desk Brescia

- Provided technical support and resolved IT issues.
- Utilized ticketing systems to manage and track problems.
- Delivered first-level technical support to users, resolving hardware and software issues promptly and
 efficiently.
- Created and updated user manuals and documentation.
- Collaborated with development teams to implement technical solutions and improve business processes.

CRM Photonic 01/2024 - 02/2024 Web Development Intern Taiwan

- A 2-month experience thanks to Rotary New Generations Service Exchange
- Followed the development of the front end part in the company, learning the daily activities and the design structure of the CRM company
- Studied various types of programming languages (HTML, CSS, Javascript, Node, React, SQL) in person with courses recommended by the staff
- Used intercultural communication skills to relate to different staff members with different levels of English

Proxi srl 01/2013 - 12/2023 Company IT Manager and Welding Machine Repairman Brescia

- Website Management
- Maintenance of company computers and hardware and software troubleshooting
- Understanding of IP addresses, including class and subnet management.
- Creation of surveillance system using cameras and special sensors
- DHCP and DNS configuration
- Active Directory management for access control and user management
- Fault analysis and repair of various types of welding machines
- Configuration of file and folder sharing with advanced access permission settings
- · Installation and configuration of company peripherals, with related driver management
- Collaboration with colleagues to find the best solution
- Organization of time based on work inflow
- Warehouse manager

EDUCATION

Degree in Computer Science

University of Verona

Computer Science Expert

Piamarta Higher Technical Institute

CERTIFICATIONS	01/2024 - 12/2024
The Complete SQL Bootcamp: Go from Zero to Hero Udemy	01/2024 - 12/2024
The Web Developer Bootcamp 2024 Udemy	01/2023 - 12/2023
The Complete Web Developer in 2023: Zero to Mastery Udemy The Complete Bythen Bostogma	01/2023 - 12/2023

The Complete Python Bootcamp

Udemy